Hello English learners and welcome to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎来到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
I'm Amira.
我是Amira。
All right, Amira is here today and she is going to tell us about the wonderful lesson
好的，今天Amira在这里，她要给我们讲讲她这次准备的精彩课程。
she has prepared this time.
她这次准备的课程。
Well, thank you, Marco.
嗯，谢谢你，Marco。
Well, today we have a very interesting lesson prepared for you.
嗯，今天我们为大家准备了一堂非常有趣的课。
It's about someone cutting in line.
是关于有人插队的事。
Cutting in line, okay.
插队，好的。
Yeah, it happens all the time and we all get very upset about it but, you know, it happens.
是啊，这种事经常发生，我们都很恼火，但你知道，它就是会发生。
Right, right.
对，对。
Well, I imagine that everyone is wondering what cutting in line is.
嗯，我想大家肯定都在好奇什么是插队。
Why don't we just listen to the dialogue one time and then when we come back Amira and
不如我们先听一遍对话，然后回来时Amira和我
I will gladly explain all the vocabulary in this dialogue.
会很乐意解释对话中的所有词汇。
Let's listen.
我们来听吧。
I can't believe it took us two hours to get here.
真不敢相信我们花了两个小时才到这里。
The traffic in New York is unbelievable.
纽约的交通真是难以置信。
Yeah, but just relax honey.
是啊，但放松点，亲爱的。
We're here and we're going on vacation.
我们到了，我们要去度假了。
In a few hours we'll be in Hawaii and you'll be on the golf course.
再过几个小时我们就在夏威夷了，你就能在高尔夫球场上了。
Oh no, look at that line.
哦不，看看那条队。
It must be a mile long.
肯定有一英里长。
There's no way I'm waiting for another two hours.
我绝不可能再等两个小时。
Honey, don't.
亲爱的，别这样。
Hey man, the end of the line is over there.
嘿，哥们，队尾在那边。
Yeah.
是啊。
No, seriously, I was here first and you can't cut in line like this.
不，说真的，我先来的，你不能这样插队。
Says who?
谁说的？
I do.
我说的。
So sue me.
有本事告我啊。
Alright, that's it.
好了，够了。
Whoa, I think there's punching.
哇，我觉得要动手了。
Yeah, I guess this guy was just a crazy, I don't know, impatient man, huh?
是啊，我猜这家伙就是个疯子，不知道，没耐心的人，是吧？
Yes, yes, but we don't want to talk about this now.
是的，是的，但我们现在不想谈这个。
But for now, we will treat some of the vocabulary and very useful phrases in the dialogue.
但现在，我们会讲解对话中的一些词汇和非常有用的短语。
Great.
太好了。
So, Marco, do you want to start?
那么，Marco，你想先开始吗？
Yes.
好的。
Let's take a look at our first word would be unbelievable.
我们来看第一个词，是unbelievable。
Unbelievable.
难以置信。
Unbelievable. Exactly, and just how you say it, it's something
难以置信。没错，就像你说的那样，它表示
incredible, something amazing.
不可思议、令人惊叹的事情。
Yeah, but I would like to point out that unbelievable was used here to describe the man's frustration.
是的，但我想指出，这里用“难以置信”来描述男人的沮丧。
He's not happy about the traffic in New York.
他对纽约的交通状况很不满。
Exactly.
没错。
Perfect.
完美。
Okay, in the next part, the woman, she's trying to calm and relax her husband.
好的，在下一部分，那位女士试图安抚她的丈夫。
And she says that they'll be in Hawaii in a few hours and you'll be on the golf course.
她说他们几个小时后就会到夏威夷，你就能去打高尔夫了。
Right.
对。
So, we'll be in Hawaii and you'll be on the golf course.
所以，我们会在夏威夷，你会在高尔夫球场上。
Yes, we'll be in Hawaii and you'll be on the golf course.
是的，我们会在夏威夷，你会在高尔夫球场上。
So, this is a great way of talking about your physical location in the future.
这是谈论未来你所在位置的一个很好的方式。
Right.
对。
So, for example, Amira, tomorrow where will you be?
比如，Amira，明天你会在哪里？
Don't worry, Marco, I'll be in the office tomorrow.
别担心，Marco，我明天会在办公室。
Perfect, right?
完美，对吧？
That's where I need you to be.
那正是我需要你在的地方。
Yes.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
All right, well, I have another interesting phrase here for you.
好了，我这里还有一个有趣的短语要告诉你。
Must be a mile long.
肯定有一英里长。
A mile long.
一英里长。
Now, that's basically not a mile, it's not a kilometer long, but it's another way of
实际上并不是一英里，也不是一公里长，但这是另一种
saying that this line is really, really long.
表示这条队伍非常非常长的方式。
Right, it's just an exaggeration.
对，这只是一种夸张的说法。
Now let's take a look at there's no way.
现在我们来看看“不可能”。
There's no way.
不可能。
Perfect.
完美。
Let's listen to some other examples on how we use there's no way in a different situation
让我们听一些其他例子，看看我们在不同情况下如何使用“不可能”，
and then we can come back and talk about it a little bit more.
然后我们再回来进一步讨论。
There's no way I can have those reports finished today.
我今天不可能完成那些报告。
The stadium is so crowded that there's no way we'll find a seat.
体育场太拥挤了，我们不可能找到座位。
Do you think Michael's going to buy that house?
你觉得迈克尔会买那栋房子吗？
There's no way he has enough money to buy it.
他绝对没有足够的钱买它。
All right, everyone.
好了，各位。
So there's no way is another way of saying it is impossible.
所以“there's no way”是“不可能”的另一种说法。
Exactly.
没错。
There's no way you should miss this podcast, right?
你绝对不能错过这个播客，对吧？
Yes.
是的。
Well, I have another phrase for you as well.
嗯，我还有一个短语要教你们。
Cut in line.
插队。
So again, we have some really good examples on how you could use this phrase in different
同样，我们有一些很好的例子，展示如何在不同情境下使用这个短语。
situations.
情况。
Let's listen to the examples and then we can come back and talk about it some more.
我们来听例子，然后回来再讨论一下。
Excuse me, I'm really late.
不好意思，我真的要迟到了。
Can I cut in line, please?
请问我能插个队吗？
I hate it when people cut in line at the bank.
我讨厌人们在银行插队。
It's so rude.
太没礼貌了。
I think it's okay when a pregnant woman cuts in line.
我觉得孕妇插队是可以的。
All right, everyone.
好了，各位。
Cut in line.
插队。
Right.
对。
So from the examples, we can understand that it means when you are standing in line somewhere
从例子中我们可以理解，它的意思是当你排队时，有人插到你前面。
and somebody gets in front of you.
对。
Right.
I have another phrase for you here.
我这里还有一个短语。
Sue me.
告我啊。
Okay.
好的。
Now, sue me is not a nice phrase.
“告我啊”可不是什么好话。
If you hear that, you know you're in trouble.
如果你听到这句话，就知道你有麻烦了。
Yeah, it's kind of rude, I guess, to say, sue me.
是的，我觉得说“告我啊”有点粗鲁。
Right.
对。
Well, it actually means like taking someone to court and asking for money because someone
嗯，它的字面意思是指把某人告上法庭并要求赔偿，因为对方以某种方式伤害了你。
has harmed you in a way.
对。
I think that we should listen to the dialogue one more time and try to figure out why he
我觉得我们应该再听一遍对话，试着理解他为什么用这个短语，以及他是否真的要告他。
used that phrase and if he's really going to take him to court.
对。
I can't believe it took us two hours to get here.
真不敢相信我们花了两个小时才到这里。
The traffic in New York is unbelievable.
纽约的交通真是难以置信。
Yeah, but just relax, honey.
是啊，不过放松点，亲爱的。
We're here and we're going on vacation.
我们到了，而且我们要去度假了。
In a few hours, we'll be in Hawaii and you'll be on the golf course.
再过几个小时，我们就在夏威夷了，你就能去打高尔夫了。
Oh, no.
哦，不。
Look at that line.
看看那队伍。
It must be a mile long.
肯定有一英里长。
There's no way I'm waiting for another two hours.
我绝不可能再等两个小时。
Honey, don't.
亲爱的，别这样。
Hey, man, the end of the line is over there.
嘿，哥们，队尾在那边。
Yeah.
是啊。
No, seriously, I was here first and you can't cut in line like this.
不，说真的，我先来的，你不能这样插队。
Says who?
谁说的？
I do.
我说的。
So, sue me.
那你去告我啊。
All right, that's it.
好了，够了。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
Now, this guy, when he says sue me, he's just being rude.
这个家伙，当他说“那你去告我啊”的时候，他只是在耍无赖。
I mean, he's just being kind of impolite and telling him, I don't care.
我的意思是，他有点不礼貌，在告诉他“我不在乎”。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
Like, you can't do anything about it.
就好像，你拿我没办法。
Yeah.
嗯。
Okay.
好的。
Today in the studio, we have a guest.
今天在录音室里，我们有一位嘉宾。
Her name is Sarah and she's from England.
她叫莎拉，来自英国。
Hi there.
你好。
Hello.
All right.
好的。
So, we're going to be asking her a couple of questions and she'll be a frequent guest
那么，我们要问她几个问题，她将成为我们节目的常客，
on our show, so you can expect to hear from her a lot.
所以你可以期待经常听到她的声音。
Well, she didn't know that.
呃，她之前不知道这事。
Yeah, it's a surprise.
是啊，是个惊喜。
She knows now.
她现在知道了。
Well, Sarah, our topic today is about jumping the queue.
那么，莎拉，我们今天的话题是关于插队。
Okay, Amira, wait.
好的，阿米拉，等等。
What is this jump the queue?
这个“jump the queue”是什么意思？
It's the same as cut in line, but in British English.
和“cut in line”一样，但这是英式英语。
Ah, okay.
啊，好的。
Yes, queuing is very important in England.
是的，排队在英国非常重要。
We're very proud of our queues.
我们为我们的排队感到非常自豪。
It's true.
确实如此。
So what would be the reaction of people if they cut in line?
如果有人插队，人们会有什么反应？
I think we do take it very seriously.
我认为我们确实很重视这件事。
I'm laughing now, but it's quite serious.
我现在在笑，但这其实很严肃。
So you don't dump the queue.
所以你不能插队。
If people jump in front of you, you get a little tuts and you shouldn't be doing that.
如果有人插到你前面，你会发出啧啧声，表示你不该这么做。
We make it very obvious.
我们会表现得很明显。
So you say it out loud?
所以你会直接说出来？
We would, you know, perhaps say something.
我们可能会，你知道，说点什么。
And we have systems, you know, in London on the Metro, on the underground, you have to
而且我们有系统，你知道，在伦敦的地铁上，在地铁里，你必须
stand on the escalators on the right and queue, and you can't jump in front.
在自动扶梯上站在右边排队，不能插队。
You have to walk on the left and queue on the right.
你必须在左边走，在右边排队。
And it's all very serious.
而且这一切都非常严肃。
There's rules and regulations.
有各种规则和规定。
Is there like a queue handbook that you have to read in high school and kind of take a
是不是有一本排队手册，你必须在高中时阅读并参加
test on?
考试？
Perhaps there should be.
也许应该有。
There should be, yeah.
应该有，是的。
Wow.
哇。
What about New York, Marco?
那纽约呢，马可？
Well, no, definitely, I guess this dialogue is similar to a reality of New York.
嗯，不，当然，我觉得这个对话和纽约的现实情况很像。
If somebody gets in front of you or cuts the line, somebody is going to say something and
如果有人插队或者加塞，肯定会有人说点什么，
probably end up in a fight if the guy is rude.
如果那个人很粗鲁，最后很可能打起来。
Yeah.
是啊。
Oh my God.
哦，天哪。
Yeah.
是啊。
Well, Sarah, why don't you tell us, is there a line or a queue for almost everything in
那么，莎拉，你跟我们说说，在英国是不是几乎每件事都要排队？
England?
英格兰？
It seems like we do just like to form a queue.
看来我们就是喜欢排队。
Yeah.
是啊。
So, you know.
所以，你知道的。
Can you think of like some other examples of where you would normally you wouldn't queue,
你能想到其他一些通常不会排队，但你还是会排的情况吗？
but you do?
但你还是会排？
Oh, gosh.
哦，天哪。
Things like in the supermarket when you're trying to find some vegetables or something,
比如在超市里，当你想挑些蔬菜之类的东西时，
I'd never push, I'd never sort of reach around or anything.
我从不推挤，也从不伸手去够或者什么的。
I'd just wait until that person had finished picking up their stuff and then go in.
我会等那个人挑完东西，然后再过去。
So, just try and...
所以，就试着……
So if like five people want to buy oranges at the supermarket, then you have a little
所以，比如有五个人想在超市买橙子，那就会有一个小小的
mini queue of five people waiting.
五个人排队的迷你队伍。
There's no sort of just shoving through to the front.
不会有人直接挤到前面去。
You just don't do that.
你绝对不会那么做。
So you don't stick your hand out and grab like a tomato.
所以你也不会伸手去抓一个西红柿。
If you do, again, you would make sure that that person knows, oh, I'm sorry, I'm just
如果你这么做了，你得确保那个人知道，哦，对不起，我只是
in a hurry or whatever.
赶时间什么的。
But yeah, it's just letting someone go before you.
但没错，就是让别人先走。
It's a courtesy, I think.
我觉得这是一种礼貌。
Okay.
好的。
It's quite important to us.
这对我们来说很重要。
All right.
好的。
Well, thank you so much, Sarah.
好的，非常感谢你，莎拉。
It was a pleasure.
这是我的荣幸。
Yeah, we'll have you back very soon.
是的，我们很快会再邀请你来的。
So, all right, we're out of time, but we'll be back tomorrow with another lesson.
好了，时间到了，但我们明天会带着另一节课回来。
And be sure to visit our website.
一定要访问我们的网站。
Don't forget that EnglishPod.com has many, many resources and also a community of users
别忘了 EnglishPod.com 有很多很多资源，还有一个用户和教师的社区，
and teachers that can help you answer questions and interact with you.
他们可以帮助你回答问题并与你互动。
Yes.
是的。
And you should definitely leave your suggestions.
而且你一定要留下你的建议。
But for now, I wish you all well and bye.
但现在，祝大家一切顺利，再见。